Guide to the Kent Family Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Kent Family Papers,
1785-1901.
Kent family.
2.10 linear ft. (5 document boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#0703
4078978
The Kent Family Papers contains letters, manuscripts, journals, and documents of the Kent family. The bulk of this material is the papers of James Kent and of William Kent. Also included are autographs, letters, and various ephemera collected by the Kent, Pinckney, and Webster families.
Biographical Note
James Kent (1763-1847) was an American jurist and legal scholar. He graduated from Yale College in 1781 and began to practice law at Poughkeepse, NY, in 1785 as an attorney, and in 1787 at the Bar. From 1791-1793 Kent was a representative of Dutchess County in the State Assembly. In 1793 he removed to New York, where Governer Jay, to whom Kent's Federalist sympathies were a strong recommendation, appointed him Master in Chancery for the City. Kent was the first professor of law at Columbia College in 1793-1798. He served the assembly again in 1796-1797. In 1797 he became Recorder of New York, in 1798 Judge of the Supreme Court of New York, in 1804 Chief Justice, and in 1814 Chancellor of New York. In 1822 Kent became a member of the convention to revise the state constitution where he unsuccessfully opposed the raising of the property qualification for African American voters. The following year Chancellor Kent resigned his office and resumed teaching at Columbia College. Out of the lectures he delivered at this time came his Commentaries on American Law (4 volumes, 1826-1830), modeled after his tremendous respect for William Blackstone's Commentaries on the Laws of England (1765-1769). Chancery law had been very unpopular during the Colonial and early American eras. Kent's opinions of this class are considered to be a basis for American equity jurisprudence. Kent was also responsible for first enunciating what would become the Cherokee doctrine, the idea that American Indian peoples, though subject, were sovereign nations.
Kent married Elizabeth Bailey, and they had four children: Elizabeth (died in infancy), Elizabeth, Mary, and William Kent.
James Kent's brother, Moss Kent (1766-1838) was a lawyer from Dutchess County, New York, and the first Surrogate of Rensselaer County, New York. He was appointed first judge of Jefferson County in 1795 and moved to Cooperstown. He was a member of the New York State Senate from 1799 to 1803 and served in the New York State Assembly in 1807 and 1810. He was appointed judge of Jefferson County in 1810, and was elected as a Federalist to the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Congresses (1813-1817) as the representative for the newly created New York's 18th congressional district. Afterword, he resumed the practice of law until his death in 1838.
William Kent (1802-1861), the only son of James Kent, was a circuit judge. He graduated from Union College with a B.A. in 1820 and a M.A. in 1823.William studied law and practiced in New York City. He was appointed Judge of the Circuit Court of New York City by Governor Seward, serving from 1841 to 1845. Kent resigned that post to accept the Royall professorship of law at Harvard, which he held in 1846-1847. He resigned that post, and returned to New York City where he became one of the founders of the New York University Law School. Shortly thereafter, in 1852, William Kent ran as a Whig for New York State Lieutenant Governor with Washington Hunt but lost to Democrat Sanford Church.
William Kent married Helen Riggs of New York City (the granddaughter of Col. William Burnett, the Surveyor-General of the Continental Army). They had one son, James, born on September 21, 1830. Judge William Kent died on January 4, 1861, at Fishkill Landing, NY.
John Seely Stone (1795-1882), whose journal is included in this collection, was a clergyman for St. Paul's Cathedral in Boston, MA, and the son in law of James Kent through his daugher, Mary. In Stone's congregation and also in the Kent's correspondence are Daniel Webster (1782-1852), American statesman, and his wife Catherine Le Roy Webster.
Lastly, the personal correspondence of Thomas Pinckney (1750-1828) and his wife are also represented in this collection. Pinckney was an early American statesman, diplomat, and veteran of both the American Revolutionary War and the War of 1812.
Scope and Content
The Kent Family Papers contains letters, manuscripts, journals, and documents of the Kent family. The bulk of this material is the papers of James Kent and of William Kent.
The correspondence represents a broad spectrum of 19th century figures prominent in the legal, political, and literary fields.
The manuscripts and documents, primarily legal in character, include essays, legal opinions by different jurists, memoranda on legal questions, and resolutions of various groups upon the death of Chancellor Kent. The documents also include wills, deeds, invitations, certificates, Chancellor Kent's legal opinions of cases submitted to him, and his notes on various authors.
In addition to material relating to the Kent family there are journals, autographs, letters, and memorabilia collected by the Pinckney and Webster families while they were in London during the 1790s and, the1830s. This includes calling cards, stamps, clippings, engravings, currency, silhouettes, and many autographs of the Revolutionary period.
There are also several diaries and journals. These include an account of a journey from New York to the eastern states; Chancellor Kent's journal on the Napoleonic Campaign, 1807-1808, his journal of the campaigns including action between the United States and Great Britain in the War of 1812, and his personal diaries, 1843-1847; and a journal of a tour in Europe, 1826, kept by Mary Kent Stone (Mrs. John Seely Stone).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 5 series. Series I, II, and IV are arranged chronologically. Series III is arranged chronologically by subject. Series V is predominantly arranged alphabetically, not including sub series 5 (Public Addresses) which is arranged chronologically.
I. Personal Correspondence
II. Legal opinions, notes, and correspondence regarding issues of the law.
III. Legal Documents and Other Items.
III.1. Diploma
III.2. Certificates to practice
III.3. Certificates of membership
III.4. Copyrights, affidavits, and insurance for James Kent's Commentaries on American Law
III.5. Property deeds and agreements
III.6. Resignation and dissolution
III.7. Wills, executor documents, and estate inventory
III.8. Resolutions on the death of James Kent
III.9. Other Items
IV. Journals and catalogs
V. Lecture notes and reading notes
V.1. Notes on the works of published single authors
V.2. Notes on the works of published multiple authors
V.3. Notes by subject
V.4. Public Addresses
V.5. Poems in manuscript
Subjects
Columbia College (New York, N.Y.)--Faculty.; Harvard University--Faculty.; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848--Correspondence; Bailey, Theodorus, 1805-1877--Correspondence; Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836--Correspondence; Baldwin, Simeon, 1761-1851--Correspondence; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852--Correspondence; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865--Correspondence; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845--Correspondence; Kent, James, 1763-1847.; Kent, William, 1858-1910.; Kent family; Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1881--Correspondence; Madison, Dorothea Payne, 1768-1849--Correspondence; Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872--Correspondence; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864--Correspondence; Stone, Mary Kent.; Stone, John Seely.; Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852--Correspondence; Pinckney family.; Webster family.; Europe--Description and travel.; Europe--History--1789-1900.; Panama Canal; United States--History--War of 1812--Campaigns.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.; United States--Politics and Government--18th Century; United States--Politics and Government--19th Century; Families--England--London.; Families--Massachusetts--Boston.; Families--New York (State)--New York.; Judges.; Lawyers.; Napoleonic Wars, 1800-1815.; Political Science--History and Theory; Presidents spouses; Seneca Indians; Autographs.; Diaries.; Engravings.; Legal opinions; Poems.; Silhouettes.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located on-site.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Kent, Louisa Gift 1965 M-65
Selected Related Material-- Other Repositories
James Kent Papers, 1779-1854, Manuscript Division, Library of Congress.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Series I. Personal Correspondence, 1787-1881 and undated
  This series contains the personal correspondence of James Kent, William Kent, and James Kent, Jr. as well as their friends and family members. It is arranged chronologically in 101 folders.
  - Transcription of letter from James Kent to N. Lawrence, December 22,1787 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Transcription of letter James Kent to Simeon Baldwin, December 4, 1790 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter from James Kent to Elizabeth Bailey Kent, May 10,1793 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Calling Cards collected by Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Pickney, 1790s (17 items) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Invitation to Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Pinckney from Jane Maxwell, the Duchess of Gordon, March 29,179- (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Invitation to Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Pinckney from the Charles Jenkinson, the First Earl of Liverpool, April 8, 179- (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Invitation to Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Pinckney from "The Mrs. Pickney," September 5, 179- (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Note from Mr. and Mrs. Church, to Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Pinckney, 179- (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Note from Mrs. Church to Thomas Pinckney, July 19, 179- (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Recommendation letter from John Adams to Oliver Wolcott, August 9, 1799 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter of permission to sell land from Anne Louise Germaine Necker, Baronne de Staël-Holstein to Moss Kent, with a note from James Kent, July 8, 1806 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Note from Henry Dundas, the First Viscount Melville to Aaron Burr, February 17,1809 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter from John Bristed to James Kent, April 4, 1818 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Request to meet for coffee from Sir Thomas Picton to Aaron Burr, November 24, 1808 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Barthold Georg Niebuhr to Aaron Burr, January 9, 1810 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter from John Quincy Adams to William Pinckney, June 12, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter from James Kent to Moss Kent, August 1, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter from James Kent to Benjamin Silliman, August 7, 1819 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Note from Isaac S. Hone to Philip Hone, February 1822 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letter from James Kent to Thomas Washington, Esq., October 6, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter from Joseph Parkes to James Kent, October 14, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Note from Henry Clay to James Kent, January 24, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Note from Daniel Webster to James Kent, January 28,1833 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letter of introduction from William Sampson to James Kent, March 30, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letter from Robert Parker to James Kent, May 10, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Note from Francis Lieber to James Kent, August 8, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter from Francis Lieber to James Kent, September 12, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Note from John Church Hamilton to James Kent, May 18, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letter from Andrew Jackson to Samuel Swartwont, November 10, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Letter from William Smith to James Kent, November 21, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Letter from Daniel Webster to James Kent, January 20, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Letter from Moss Kent to William Kent, February 5,1837 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Letter from Henry Clay to James Kent, February 22, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letter from John Quincy Adams to James Kent, March 2, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letters of Catherine Maria Sedgwick, June 14, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Photostat of letter from Carper Pruyn to James Kent, January 28, 1839 (re: the death of Stephen Van Rensselaer) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Condolence letter from James Kent to Cornelia Paterson Van Rensselaer, January 30, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Note from Angela Georgina Burdett-Coutts, 1st Baroness Burdett-Coutts, to Mr. and Mrs. Daniel Webster, June 26, 1839. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Invitation from Sir Edward Hall and Lady Alderson to Mr. and Mrs. Daniel Webster, June 29, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Note from John Curteis to Caroline Le Roy Webster, July 6, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Note from Lady Catherine Pollok Manners Stepney to Mr. and Mrs. Daniel Webster, July 13, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letter from John Kenyon to Daniel Webster, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letter from Lady Georgiana Fane to Caroline Le Roy Webster, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Note from Thomas Whitmore to the London Horticultural Society, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Letter from Eliphalet Nott to William Henry Seward, January 26, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Letter from George Evans to James Kent, May 10, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Letter from Josiah Quincy to James Kent, March 16, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Letter of thanks from President John Tyler to Caroline Le Roy Webster, June 14, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Letter in French to James Kent from Unknown, June 15, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Letter from Henry Black to James Kent November28 1841 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Note from Dorothea (Dolly) Payne Todd Madison (Mrs. James) to Daniel Webster, April 5, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - From Dorothea (Dolly) Payne Todd Madison (Mrs. James) to Caroline Le Roy Webster, June 1, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Letter from Daniel Webster to James Kent, December 17, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Letter from James Kent to Daniel Webster, December 21, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Letter from Edward Everett to James Kent, December 26, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Letter from William G. Hocker to James Kent, May 20, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Letter from Edward Everett to James Kent, June 12, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Letter from George William Frederick Howard (Viscount Morpeth), 7th Earl of Carlisle, to James Kent, June 15, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Letter from Thomas Cowperthwait & Co. to James Kent, August 21, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Letter from Simon Greenleaf to James Kent, September 9, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Letter from Robert Greenhow to James Kent, April 19,1847. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - From James Kent to William Bradford Reed, July 4, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - From William Pennington to William Kent, December 25, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Letter of condolensce from the Supreme Court of Tennessee to William Kent, January 8,1848 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - From (photostat) from William Charles Macready to William Kent, December 7, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - (Photostat) from William T.L. Smithy to Winfield Scott, December 16,1848 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - (Photostat) from William Charles Macready to William Kent, December 17, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - From Samuel Miller to William Kent, January 29, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - (Photostat) from William Charles Macready to William Kent, May 12, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - (Photostat) from George Ticknor Curtis to William Kent, June26 1849 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - (Photostat) from George Ticknor Curtis to William Kent, June 30, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - From Abijah Hubbard Moss to William Kent, July 5, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - From Hamilton Fish to William Kent, July 12, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - From Abner Morse to William Kent, September 22, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Note from George I. Cornell to William Kent, October 1, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Letter from "T." O'Connell to William Kent, October 24, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Letter from William Pennington to William Kent, February 4, 1850. (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Letter from James Walker to William Kent, February 15, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Letter from James Walker to William Kent, February 19, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Telegram from James Monroe & Co. to James Kent Jr., March1, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Letter from Martin Van Buren to "G." Kemble, October26 1856 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Letter from Henry Codman Potter to Helen Riggs Kent, January 6, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Letter from Theodorus Bailey to Helen Riggs Kent, January 8,1861 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Note from Nathaniel Prentiss Banks to James Kent, Jr. July 3, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Note from Joseph B. Bradley to James Kent Jr, February 8, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Note from Noah Davis to James Kent Jr, February 14, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Note from Charles O'Conor to James Kent Jr. July 30, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Note from Henry Wadsworth Longfellow to James Kent Jr (attached to an engraving of Longfellow), re: the word "lily pad." October 25, 1874. (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Letter from Benjamin D. Silliman to James Kent Jr, November 3,1877 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Note from William Ferdinand Morgan to Emilly Taylor Lorillard, April 30, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Note from Sydney Smith to Unknown person, undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Note from Sir and Lady John Nicholl to Mr. and Mrs. Pinckney, undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Note from William Charles Macready to unknown person, undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Note from William Charles Macready to William Kent, undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Letter from Mary Alsop King (Mrs. Rufus?) to Elizabeth Mott Pinckney, undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Letter from Mary Alsop King (Mrs. Rufus?) to Elizabeth Mott Pinckney, undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Letter from James Kent to "his cousin," undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - From Lord Jeffrey Francis to James Kent, undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - From Charles Gould to James Kent, December 20, undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Note from "Dupin" to James Kent (written in the third person), undated (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - From Thomas Denman (Baron) to unknown, undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
- Series II. Legal Opinions, Notes, and Correspondence Regarding Issues of the Law, 1791-1851 and undated
  Most items of correspondence in this series are of William Kent and James Kent but there are several without proprietary signatures or penned by other men of the law, for example Martin Van Buren and George S. Yerger as well as other individuals. This series is arranged chronologically in 82 folders.
  - Statement on the state debt of New York and of the securities in the Treasury, in the hand of James Kent, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Legal opinion on debts for Sedgwick and Bleeker, in the hands of James Kent, July 1805 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Claim of the Orphan Asylum Society of New York against his estate, Peter McCartee et al executors, opposing the claim of his widow, Elizabeth Jacobs; addressed to James Kent and signed by Isaac A. Johnson and David Bayard Ogden., December 12, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Joseph Kinnicutt Angell to James Kent and separate notations in Kent's hand on Sir Matthew Hale and the Coin Law, February23 1828. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Agreement of Land: Eliza R. Armstrong to sell property to Nicholas Cruger, signed by Armstrong, April 25, 1828. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Martin Van Buren to Preserved Fish, September 19, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Martin Van Buren to Preserved Fish, October 2, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - On Arkansas and Texas Land Co., unknown author, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Legal opinion on the will of George (?) Edwards, James Kent, February14 1833 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Legal opinion on Underhill vs. Van Cortlandt, James Kent, March 26, 1834 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Legal opinion on the will of Henry Churchill, related correspondence from Bate & McKissock, James Kent, March 1838 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Legal opinion on Baltimore vs .White & Sons, James Kent, March 24, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Legal opinion for Commercial Bank of Florida, James Kent, September7, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Legal opinion on Brown Bros. & Co. vs. Birkenhead & Co., James Kent, September 14, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Legal opinion for the Munn Illionois Land Co. land title, James Kent, December 4. 1838 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Draft of marriage settlement between the son of William Brown (Alexander) and the daughter of his brother, James Brown. December 19, 1838. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Legal opinion on Ohio Life Insurance & Trust Co. move to New York, James Kent, December 1838 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Legal opinion on New York, Providence, and Boston Railroad Mortgage, James Kent, January 14, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Legal opinion on an Indian title and fraud, James Kent, February13 1839 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Legal opinion on Joseph S. Kennedy et al. vs. William Hall et al., James Kent, March1, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Legal opinion on Markle heirs vs. Rapp heirs with related letter from Rose Chauncey, James Kent, July 1839 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Legal opinion on John K. Boyer vs. the Illionois Canal Co., James Kent, September24 1839 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Letter from B'Nai Ishurun Congregation requesting legal opinion from James Kent, with notes in Kent's hand, September 29, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Legal opinion on the will of James D'Wolf with related letter from Jonathon Prescott Hall, James Kent, October1839 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Legal opinion on the will of James D'Wolf, James Kent, October 30, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Legal opinion on the Wisconsin Marine & Fire Insurance Co., James Kent, November 29, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Legal opinion on Seneca Indians vs. Ogden & Fellows, James Kent, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Request for legal opinion from David Sears to James Kent, December 22, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Letter from David Sears regarding advice given by James Kent, January 11, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding the Bank of Kentucky and a fraudulent stock issue with a note by James Kent, January 30, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Legal opinion on North American Trust and Banking Co. vs. R.M. Blatchfordet et.al., April 27, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Legal opinion on North American Trust and Banking Co. vs. R.M. Blatchfordet et al., May 1841 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Legal opinion on North American Trust and Banking Co. vs. R.M. Blatchfordet et al., May 13, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Legal opinon on Whiton & Hulburt vs. Butterworth & Smith, James Kent, June 7, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Legal opinion on John W. Leavitt vs. North American Fire Insurance Co., James Kent, October 15, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Legal opinion on Trinity House of Quebec vs. the bark Miramiche, James Kent, November 1, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Legal opinion on Brigantine Xenophon vs. the bark Delia, James Kent, December 10, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Legal opinion on Gopher & Dakin vs. Southard & Emerson, James Kent, December 21, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Legal opinion on George M. Woolsey et al vs. Edward Curtis, James Kent, December 23, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Legal opinion on the Public School Society, James Kent, April 11, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Legal opinion on the Tennessee Railroad with notes by James Kent, George S. Yerger, September 3, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Resolution on the Hiwapee Rail Road, from the minutes of the board, Union Bank of Tennessee, September 6, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Request for legal opinion from the Public School Society of New York Executive Committee to James Kent, July 14, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Indictment in the case of Henry Harrison vs. The Robert & Ann, Vice Admiralty Court of Canada, August 20, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Request for legal opinion from Vincennes University board of Trustees, James Kent, November 15, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 45)